<system>
  <title>
    ALL
  </title>
  <acronym-expansion>
    ALL Language Learning
  </acronym-expansion>
  <short-description>
    Language Acquisition ITS
  </short-description>
  <medium-description>
    ALL is  a system  that supports many  tasks of  language learning.
    Knowledge of  other languages is deemed essential  to education of
    the mind and, when combined  with CLEAR, opens the door to immense
    quantities of knowledge.  ALL  supports this task for both written
    and  spoken  language (a  necessity).   It  interfaces with  Bard,
    CLEAR, and PICForm.
  </medium-description>
  <long-description>
    <p>
      First of all, there is an immense amount of knowledge that has
      been written.  To expand our minds we ought to learn foreign
      languages.  We choose to learn various languages based on their
      strengths and weaknesses.  Chinese will be useful for PICForm.
      Sanskrit is a formal language with a 5000 year history, some of
      which was oral.  Gaelic was oral as well.  Hebrew is useful for
      certain reasons, etc,etc,etc.
    </p>
    <p>
      In order to facilitate language learning we have several
      features.  The first is our system models the various languages
      that we are to learn.  It knows our vocabulary and is able to
      see patterns in the languages and teach us through analogical
      reasoning and custom Mnemonics.  For each language a grammar is
      used, as well as for spoken languages a pronunciation system
      (TTS).  The user is taught the basic 1400 or so words in each
      important language and continually refreshed upon them, and
      advanced vocabulary is developed wherever possible.  They are
      incorporated in communication with the user to preserve use.
      Ancient and modern texts in the appropriate language are often
      read by CLEAR to the user.  Interesting artifacts in each
      language are documented and exposed (e.g. in Sanskrit there are
      poems that read forward as well as backwards, in Chinese there
      is a poem composed entirely of "Shi", etc.)
    </p>
    <p>
      Spoken models are contrasted with the TTS and corrective
      feedback is given.  By knowing what the user knows about the
      language, custom dictionary entries are generated based on the
      vocabulary the user already possesses.  Furthermore, their
      language acquisition helps us to formalize the semantics of all
      the different languages.  A model of common myths for each
      language is created to help expedite learning for large groups.
    </p>
    <p>
      Incorporate Justin's writing on this topic when we have internet
      access.   One   subsystem  of  ALL  is  Termios   which  is  the
      terminology  management server.  It  is responsible  for knowing
      all the word  definitions.  Naturally it makes use  of many data
      sources: WordNet, OpenCyc,  Sensus, EuroWordNet, OMCSNet, dictd,
      etc., as well as  many programs: Verber, Peterson's WSD, FLogic,
      Gate.  The basic goal is to provide some level of meaning for as
      much  terminology as  possible,  as well  as construct  thematic
      mappings.
    </p>
  </long-description>
</system>